## **Cody Miu**

## **Software Developer**

cody.miu@gmail.com | 514-430-7061 | Montreal

Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

#### Summary

Dedicated junior developer with 3 years of experience in a dynamic and fast-paced industry. Proficiency with Python and web development demonstrated in personal portfolio and through Computer Science and Web Programming certificates from HarvardX. Looking to join a talented team to grow my skills as a software developer.

**Languages:** Python, JavaScript, HTML and CSS **Frameworks:** Django, React and Bootstrap **Databases:** SQL (PostgreSQL, SQLite)

Other: Git, Linux, Cloud infrastructure (Heroku), MVC

design pattern

Spoken Languages: English, French and Romanian

### **Technical Projects**

All projects are full stack applications built with Python (Django) and PostgreSQL on the server side, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap on the front-end, structured with MVC and stored on the Heroku cloud platform.

#### Project Tracking App (Workboard) | Website

- Built a project tracking application to organize workflow into boards with different columns and movable cards
- Implemented mobile responsiveness through Flexbox, dynamic UI, and database manipulation/reordering through API calls and Python logic
- Challenges included security and having users dynamically create, edit, delete and move elements on a web page

#### Social Networking App | Website

- Built a social platform where registered users can post, like and follow others (unregistered users can only view)
- Implemented JavaScript promises, JSON, Bootstrap pagination and dynamic UI

#### E-commerce App | Website

- Built an e-commerce auction platform where users post listings, place bids, comment and add those listings to a watchlist
- Implemented security, Django Models and forms, view items by category, and notify auction winner

#### Email App | Website

- Built an email client where users can send, receive, reply and archive emails through API calls
- Implemented dynamic User Interfaces by creating HTML elements through JavaScript

#### **Education & Certifications**

## CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript HarvardX - Issued 11/2021

## CS50's Introduction to Computer Science

HarvardX - Issued 06/2021

# BCom; Information Systems Major, Computer Science Minor

McGill University - Graduated 12/2017

#### **Professional Experience**

#### **IT Talent Management Advisor**

04/2020 - Present; LRO

10/2018 - 03/2020; Randstad Technologies

04/2018 - 10/2018; Intudio

- Provided full lifecycle technical recruitment and coordinated work with team and clients to meet deadlines
- Automated processes in the Application Tracking System to improve workflow and mentored colleagues on boolean expressions
- Helped colleagues understand the nuances between IT roles and products